Mobile: +91 8920906049 mailto: abidkshafi@gmail.com

SENIOR PROJECT MANAGER II GIS II BUSINESS ANALYST

PROJECT MANAGEMENT II DATA MANAGEMENT SOLUTIONS II GIS ANALYSIS AND INTEGRATION

I am an accomplished Business Analyst and Senior Project Manager with over 14+ years experience in an established history of results-driven project managements, data/system design and analysis and a broad range of project experience specializing in Geographic Information Systems. May ability to manage simultaneous projects and forge long-term relationships with clients and functional groups has led to a successful track record in a wide variety of industries and roles. I possess the analytical thinking abilities to meet objectives independently, and consistently meet deadlines within fast-paced environments.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Team Collaboration	Process Improvement	Change Management
Resource Allocation	Vendor Management	Geographic Information Systems
Business Development	Training & Development	Operations/Support Management
Client Relations	System Integration	Forecasting, Strategic Planning
Deadline Management	Cartographic Design	Geo-database Management
Workflow Development	Enterprise GIS	Aerial/Satellite Image Interpretation
Research and Data Mining	Quality Assurance & Control	Project Conception to Production

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>GM- Operation and Sales - Geo-spatial Technologies , Applied GeoTech Solutions Private Limited, A532 Logix</u> Technova, Sector-132, Noida 201304, May 2019 to present

Applied GeoTech Solutions (AGS) is a privately owned and ISO certified Company dedicated to providing cost effective and reliable professional consultancy services and solutions pertaining to the deployment of CAD/BIM & GIS/Geospatial/LiDAR Mapping & technology both in public & private sector organizations throughout the worldwide.

GM- GEOSPATIAL SERVICES & CAD ENGINEERING OPERATIONS, Pan Tech World, LLC, 14090 Southwest Freeway, Suite# 300, Sugar Land, Texas- 77478, September 2016 to April 2018.

Pan Tech World, LLC is one of the CAD Data Conversion & Geospatial Mapping Service providers in Sugar Land, Texas-USA with its presence in Noida, India. PTW consists of team who are experts and best solution providers in GIS & IT industry with an experience in delivering projects ranging from utility management to energy site intelligence for leading companies.

<u>GM- OPERATIONS, GIS TRANS SOLUTIONS (P) LTD, C-4/197, 2ND FLOOR – SECTOR 36, NOIDA-DELHI (INDIA), April</u> 2016 to August 2016

GIS Trans Solutions, LLC is a leading GIS company offering Geo-Spatial Services, Information Technology Services and Solutions to clients across the globe. Services offered by us are effectively useful for Utilities, Real estate, Disaster Management, E-governance, Land Management and over many other business verticals. We at GTS understand the quality and delivery requirements of our valued customers worldwide. Our strength lies in our vast international experience and understanding of domain specific requirements.

<u>Dy. GENERAL MANAGER, ADROITEC INFORMATION SYSTEM PVT. LTD, C-130, SECTOR-2, NOIDA/DELHI (INDIA)</u> Client/Vendor: CenterPointEnergy/AFDS (Applied Field Data System Inc) & HirePower Personnel Inc, Houston, Texas. USA, March 2010 to April 2016

Adroitec is Global Consultancy and Services Company with state-of-the-art development centers in India and 100% owned US based subsidiary HOPE Consulting Inc, and highly qualified and experienced professionals. Adroitec drives to stay at the forefront of technology and a track record of excellence make Adroitec ideally suited to be 'right outsourcing partner'. Adroitec Apart from being 'Gold Partner' of PTC for all their products and of 'Oracle' for their world renowned Project Management Solution 'Primavera', Siemen's Industry Software for Digital manufacturing Solutions, distributes products of the best MNC's in India in the area of AEC/CAD/CAM/GIS.

MY PRIMARY RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ✓ Lead multiple GIS Projects and Business Development Operations, and liaison between the Client/Vendor and internal project groups.
- Providing quality control on the work done by project team into CenterPoint Energy's Geo-database.
- ✓ Participating in the special projects, conduct quality review in Geo-database and data products and providing solutions to the client/vendor.
- ✓ Update, critique and create documentation for all procedures and processes based on the client standards.
- Manage spatial data specific to the project team, in accordance with the corporate standards.
- Provide training to new recruited staff in internal project team and for on-site newly hired client staff.
- ✓ Coordinating with client and project teams to develop and maintain standards and provide technical support and query analysis.
- ✓ Documentations, Presentations and Technical training for project staff and Client.
- ✓ Business Analyst role- solicited business requirements and provided detailed impact analysis for enhancements, major upgrades, and new projects and applications.
- ✓ Engaged in business development efforts with the new and existing clients.
- ✓ Coordinate with Clients and project team to determine project scope, budget, schedule and deliverables.
- ✓ Develop project work plans and determine resource requirements, monitor and control project expenses within allotted budget.
- ✓ Managed, coordinate and oversee project activities to ensure the project deliverables meet quality standards and business requirements.

DEPUTY MANAGER CAD/GIS SERVICES, DIMENSION INDIA NETWORK PRIVATE LIMITED, B-106, SECTOR-2, NOIDA U.P (INDIA)

Client/Vendor: Dimension India Network, January 2010 to March 2010

Dimensioni, a renowned Global Outsourcing Company established in 1999. Dimension I provides best in class services in CAD/GIS, Web Application Development, Paper to Auto Cad Drafting and GIS Conversion Services to the clients globally. A blend of business and technology professionals with experience of working with some of the biggest names in the corporate world and the most challenging projects for over 10 years, the team is the right mix to deliver quality solutions every time.

SENIOR PROJECT OFFICER (CAD & GIS SERVICES), ISERVICES INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED ((A Group of iEnergizer), D-10, SECTOR-2, NOIDA U.P (INDIA)

Client/Vendor: SOURCECORP Inc/CenterPoint Energy/AFDS (Applied Field Data System Inc, Houston, Texas. USA, September 2004 to January 2010.

iServices provides Geographical Information Services and Health Care and Insurance Solutions to the several clients globally.

MY PRIMARY RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ✓ Proposal writing for New Projects
- ✓ Project Man-hour and Cost Estimation
- ✓ Project Coordination
- ✓ Team building and Coordination
- ✓ Client Communication for data inputs, technical queries and teleconference.
- ✓ Client Engagement and Project Scheduling
- ✓ Preparation of Weekly/ Monthly Production Report
- ✓ Technical Queries and troubleshooting.
- ✓ Work allocation and training to new staff
- ✓ Documentation, Presentation etc,

PROJECT DESCRIPTIONS

1# VPN BASED GIS DATA UPDATION/CREATION ON ARCMAP/ARCINFO:

Project Electrical, Gas & Land Base utility Design and Drawing project for facility Management of USA client (as Centre point Energy) of Houston, Arkansas, Minnesota, Mississippi, East Texas, South Texas, Louisiana South, Louisiana North & Oklahoma States.

Main motive of this project is updating data of the installed the Utility on Client customized software by accessing the digital images of work orders and land plats in FileNet via Internet.

This is an AM/FM (Automated Mapping and Facilities Management) Utility Project.

Automated mapping/facilities management :-Automated cartography or geographic information systems used by utilities and public works organizations for storing, manipulating, and mapping facility information such as pipe and road networks, Electrical and Gas distribution layouts etc....

The main Objective of this Project is to digitize (install or update) the Utility features by accessing the Client's server with help of Internet as per the inputs received.

LANDBASE DEVELOPMENT:

This project is carried out for the execution of below mentioned projects. The overall scope of this project is the digitization of multiple layers of primitive spatial features like Lot line, Street Centerline, Row Line, Building Polygons etc that provide a locational reference to other spatial features in the spatial database.

LOCAL NATURAL GAS DISTRIBUTION:

This project is carried out for Centre Point Energy a well known gas and electrical utility serving company in the Houston metropolitan area having local natural gas distribution businesses in six states in the eastern half of the U.S. The overall scope of this project is the digitization and updation of natural gas pipelines and other fittings as per the various standards and guidelines set by the client in Arc GIS 9.2. The objective of this project is to develop a high quality digital output that can be used for the Repair and Maintenance works. The specifications are different for different states but the overall scope remains unchanged.

ELECTRICAL TRANSMISSION AND DISTRIBUTION:

This project is also carried out for Centre point Energy electric transmission serving company for the Houston metropolitan area in the United States. The overall scope of this project is the digitization and updation of various electrical cables (Over Head Secondary and Primary, One Two and Three phase Underground distribution lines) and various fittings (Transformers, Fuse, Pedestals, Poles, Pull Box etc.) with the help of documents with reference to the various standards and guidelines set by the client in Arc GIS 9.2.. The objective of this project is to develop a high quality digital output that can be used for the Repair and Maintenance works in case of an outage.

AFDS & HPP CLIENT QC PROJECT:

This project is external quality check for client work that has been digitized by diffrenet-2 vendors in above all categories for.

DATA CORRECTION PROJECT:

Map correction work comes under this project as per new Landbase requirements in above entire projects for GAS, ELECTRIC, LANDBASE and AFDS QC.

Role: Project Manager

Period of Job: April, 2004 to Present

Project Owner: Applied Field Data System Inc, HirePower Personnel Inc,/Center Point Energy, Inc. Houston, Texas,

USA

Reference information: Ishu Wadwani & Marilyn Robinson

2# LANDB RECORDS & DIGITAL IMAGE CLARIFICATION

The project involved development of city maps and modeling of the civil lines. This project also involved linking up the consumer data with the main hub. It also involved identification and gradient of the civil lines.

Role: Project Manager

Period of Job: April, 2010 to June, 2011

Project Owner: Auger, Inc. U.K.

Reference information: Mr. Mahesh Chand

3# LAND USE AND LAND CLASSIFICATION USING PHOTOGRAMMETRY AND IMAGE DATA

(1) Sanborn was to provide imagine raster data set highlighting potential impervious surfaces.

Adroitec was to review these images and correct the errors in the impervious potential map based on the underlying imagery and to clean up raster data with an extra shape file of information to track any questions or any comments of the data provided. The work related to States of Hawai, Kentuki, etc.

- (2) Updating the RFR references for some automated land based mapping, including labeled impervious data set in shape file format for selected areas of the Common Wealth of Massachusetts. It also included various image classification.
- (3) Similar work for many other cities was also undertaken.

Role: Project Manager

Period of Job: May, 2010 to March, 2011

Project Owner: The Sanborn Map Company, Inc, Colorado Springs, CO 80920 – 5358

Reference information: Mr. Mahesh Chand

4# LAND PARCEL MAPPING & IMAGE CLASSIFICATION

Editing the automated pilot to classification involving digitization and recoding polygons, so that the classification represents the imagery, using ARCINFO 10 Geo database and shape file.

Role: Project Manager

Period of Job: April, 2011 to October, 2011 Project Owner: Photo Science Inc., USA Reference information: Mr. Mahesh Chand

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

- ✓ Master of Business Administration in 2005 at Bundelkhand University, Jhansi.
- ✓ Bachelor of Science in 2001 at Meerut University, Meerut.
- ✓ Certification in GEO-INFORMATICS in 2015 at NAM Institute of Professional Studies, New Delhi
- ✓ Intermediate in 1998 from UP Board Allahabad
- ✓ Matriculation in 1996 from UP Board Allahabad

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ✓ GIS business operations expertise and project management.
- ✓ ESRI's ArcGIS 9.3 and 10 –
- Geo-referencing, coordinate systems and projections.
- Field data collection and integrate GPS data with ArcGIS.
- Cartography, work area polygons.
- Raster classification, remote sensing image analysis.
- Data acquisition and analysis, building geo-databases.
- ✓ Create and execute queries to generate custom reports from ArcGIS.
- Experience working with customized ESRI software.
- ✓ Custom GIS applications such as FileNet and Work order tracking system.
- ✓ Office Documentation: Microsoft Office 2010 and 2007.
- ✓ Operating Systems: Windows 2008 server, Windows 7, Vista and XP Professional.
- ✓ Reporting: Business Explorer, Microsoft Excel and Web Reporting.

PERSONAL PARTICULARS

Date of Birth : June' 1981
Nationality : Indian
Total Work Experience : 15+ Years
Experience in Arc-GIS : 14+ Years

Onsite Experience : Yes (multiple entries)

Passport No : G7982254

Valid US- Visa (Business) : Yes for ten years (Oct 15, 2008 to Oct 13, 2018)

Gap in the work experience : No

Language Know : English, Hindi and Urdu

Communicate address : B-65, Sector-101, Shivnagar Colony Salarpur, Noida

REFERENCES

Mohammad Ali: President, at Royal Technocarts Inc. 9896 Bissonnet Street, Suite# 350, Houston, Texas 77036, United States of America.

Ishu Wadwani: President, at AFDS (Applied Field Data System Inc. 2717 Commercial Center Blvd, Suit# E200, Katy, Texas 77494 United States of America.

Mr. Saroop Chand: Managing Director, at Adroitec Information Systems India Limited, C-130, Sector-2, Noida-201301, UP (India)

Mr. Mahesh Chand: Corporate Consultant, at Adroitec Information Systems India Limited, C-130, Sector-2, Noida-201301, UP (India)

Place: Noida (Delhi)

Thanking you, Abid K Shafi